#大家好 兄弟家池塘的魚跑出了好多來呀
Hi everyone! A lot of fish run away from my buddy's pond.
#你看就在下面
Look! They're just under the water.
#現在看到三條 紅色的
Now I can see three fish, red fish,
#紅色的鯉魚哦
red carps.
#兄弟家的池塘
My buddy opened the dam,
#那水壩都開啦
of his pond.
#全部魚都跑出來啦
So the fish are running away.
#叫我幫他釣一點回去
He asked me to catch some of them back.
#哇 好多魚呀 小魚大魚
Wa! A lot of fish, big and small.
#釣不回去的話
If I can't catch any,
#我還 我還帶了那個魚網過來
I, I have a fishing net with me as well.
#釣不到我就網
I'll be very ready to use it.
#把這個綫搞一下
Let's take care of the fishing line first.
#這麼多魚
There're so many fish,
#看都看得到 它竟然不吃
I can see so many, but none of them eat the bait.
#太奇怪啦
It's weird.
#不就在你眼前嗎 幹嘛不吃嘞
Can't you see the food right in front of you? Why don't you eat it?
#這個不是嗎
Isn't this the bait?
#眼瞎了 他的魚
His fish must be blind.
#在他的面前他都不咬
It's right in front of them but they don't even bite.
#氣死我了
Damn it!
#最後一次
Your last chance!
#快點咬鈎哦 不咬鈎
Come onto the hook! Otherwise the net is coming.
#不咬鈎我放網了哦
All of you will be captured.
#大小通殺哦
Big and small.
#看得到它又 基本不咬
I can see them. But, they are not biting at all.
#收起來
Enough!
#這個東西不好玩
It's not fun at all.
#我拿網來
I'll bring the net.
#就知道我釣不到
I know that the fishing rod is no good.
#所以我早就帶了副網過來
So I come with the net.
#備用
Just in case.
#放網
Let's go!
#好啦好啦 不要放了 我這裡放著下
Alright, alright! You can stop. I'll put on this side.
#漁網在那邊放著
I'll keep the net over there for a while,
#我來在這邊釣一下魚 看能不能釣的[SIC]到
and see if I have any luck with the fishing rod here.
#大不大 甚麼魚
Is it big? What kind of fish is it?
#哈哈 不要跑了 跑了晚飯都沒得吃了
Haha! Don't run away! Or we'll have nothing for dinner.
#慢點 慢點 不要拔斷了
Be gentle, be gentle! Don't break it.
#慢一點 你這樣會拔斷的 這樣
Be gentle, be gentle. You're going to break the line, come on!
#就鈎到一點嘴皮
It's barely hooked onto its mouth.
#抓住它 不要跑了
Catch it! Don't let it go!
#你看 幸好鈎著它的嘴皮
Look! Luckily, it's hooked onto its mouth.
#不要走掉啦 不要走掉啦 要不到這裡解 拿上岸去解
No, no! Don't let it go! Don't untie it here. Go back to the shore first.
#一要跳著了 哈哈
Don't jump! Ha ha
#哇
Wa!
#這次釣到一條那麼大的鯉魚
We got such a huge carp this time!
#差不多三斤
It's almost one and a half kilo.
#剛才還釣了條那個草魚 跑啦
I've got a grass carp as well. But it has run away already.
#現在釣了條鯉魚
I still have this fish at least.
#誒 有一條哦
Eh! There's one.
#你看
Look!
#網了有幾條
There're some fish on the net.
#小魚
Small fish
#我們現在回去 回去把它解開
Let's go back now and untie them at home.
#這天色有點晚啦
It starts getting dark now.
你看
Look!
#這個魚
We're back,
#剛拿回來
with the fish.
#解一下
I'll untie them.
#衣服都濕啦
My clothes are all wet.
#換了件衣服
So I've got changed.
#你看 這條
Look! This fish,
#這條被捆在這裡
got stuck here.
#你看 網了就網了那麼一點點
Look! We got just a bit here with the net.
#幸好搞了一條大貨
Luckily we have this big guy.
#今晚我們把它煎了
Tonight I'll fry it,
#紅燒 (註︰他根本就沒有做紅燒)
braise it.
#紅燒鯉魚
Braised carp.
#好
Good!
#我去生火
I'll set the fire.
#放點這個鹽
Rub the, I mean, salt.
#撒到它傷口上
onto it's wound.
#多撒一點
More salt!
#太慘了你
I feel sorry for you.
#誰叫你
It's all because,
#誰叫你們是一道菜呢
it's all because you are a a dish.
#加點嘴巴上
Some on the mouth too.
#加點這個
Put some, well,
#醬油
soy sauce,
#生抽
the light one.
#料酒
The cooking wine,
#料酒被我們
the cooking wine has been,
#我 我弟喝光啦
drunk up by, by us, I mean by my younger brother.
#現在料酒就沒有啦
So I don't have any cooking wine now.
#下次叫攝影小哥
I'll see if Mr. Cameraman can bring me some,
#順便帶一點過來
when he comes here.
#生薑
Ginger
#搞點生薑去腥
The ginger can reduce the fishy smell.
#這樣 給他們
Then, I'll,
#給它們擦一擦
I'll rub them,
#擦擦它們的傷口
rub their wounds.
#鹽也可以是消毒的
In fact salt can sterilize.
#我幫你消消毒
Let me sterilize you guys.
#先腌半個小時左右
We first marinate it for about half an hour.
#我們就
Then we can,
#直接把它煎了
simply fry it.
#半個小時再說
I'll come again after half an hour.
#你看 上次兄弟帶過來的寬油
Look! This is the "kaun you" (oil) brought to me by my buddy last me.
#搞點來
I use it now.
#先把這個魚抓去炸一下
I'll have this fish deep-fried first.
#這個魚鈎在哪裡 (註︰原字幕沒有這句)
Where is the hook?
#把它提前下鍋吧
Put it into the wok first.
#哇 這個魚 做好了
Wa! This fish, is done now.
#我搞 我們搞點料來 (註︰視頻重覆了「搞點料來」，但字幕沒有顯示)
I'll, we'll fetch the side ingredients, side ingredients.
#搞點
Some,
#生薑
ginger.
#豆瓣醬
Bean paste sauce
#現在加點葱花
And now some spring onions.
#好啦好啦好啦好啦 把它淋下去
Ok, ok, ok ok. I'll pour it onto the fish.
#與肉均沾
Mix it well with the fist.
#旁邊多粘一點
More on the two sides.
#哇 好香啊
Wa! It smells so good.
#把它端過去先
I'll bring it over there first.
#還有其他菜要煮
There're still other dishes.
#你看這個魚 做好啦
Look! The fish is done now.
#很好吃的哦
It tastes really good.
#嗯
Um!
#可以
Not bad
#這是做紅燒魚做的[SIC]最成功的一次
This is my single most successful braised fish,
#最漂亮
and the prettiest.
#沾著 粘著這個裝 更美味
It tastes even better with, with the sauce.
#你看 搞了 差不多一個小時
Look! I've spent almost an hour.
#終於把這個飯做好了
Finally the dinner is ready.
#一個人幹活
One person cooks,
#全部吃飯
everybody eats.
#你看
Look!
#菜煮好了 他們全部都過來了
There're all coming when the dinner is ready.
#都是兄弟
They're all buddies and brothers.
#沒辦法
Can't be too calculating.
#我們準備吃飯啦
It's time for dinner now.
#好啦
Alright!
#今天的視頻就到這裡啦
The video ends here.